<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Film Restoration on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/film-restoration/</link><description>Recent content in Film Restoration on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/film-restoration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reconstructing Selvigs Norgesfilm - Part 1</title><link>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-11-01-nvn-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-11-01-nvn-part-1/</guid><description>A few years back I undertook a large film reconstruction of the Norwegian silent documentary Selvig&amp;rsquo;s Norgesfilm (1929), also known as Norge vårt Norge, i toner og billeder. It was a challenging undertaking that kept me busy for a few years. Due to the complexity of the project and research, I&amp;rsquo;ve never been happy with how I managed to document all the work I put into it. My sources were a sprawling mess, and the comparison and identification of film elements quite exhausting.</description></item><item><title>The reconstruction of 'Norge vårt Norge: i toner og billeder'</title><link>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-10-30-norge-vaart-norge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-10-30-norge-vaart-norge/</guid><description>Background Project initiation Trondheim project (Trondheinsreisen) + jubilee Film metadata Director Basic information Norwegian travelogues Se norge Norgesfilmer Sources Film materials Originals (list all available nitrate elements) Messy provenance Uoversiktlig, blandet med andre titler Previous preservation (list all available safety elements) Messy provenance Materials missing, incorrect copying history Swedish version Map of film materials and generations Paper materials Censorship logs Parts not existing in film materials or EDL/intertitle list Can be used to identify missing materials, but cannot be used to reconstruct censored version Intertitle list + EDL list Uncertain provenance Challenging to use without interpretation.</description></item></channel></rss>