<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Preservation at the National Library of Norway</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024/05/29/digital-preservation-at-the-national-library-of-norway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024/05/29/digital-preservation-at-the-national-library-of-norway/</guid><description>Presentation at the Digital libraries: storage for now and forever conferenence hosted by the IFLA Preservation and Conservation Center at the National Library of Poland. The presentation is a crash course through digital storage and digital preservation practices at the National Library of Norway over the past 20 years. It concludes with current status and our future plans.
Link to PDF
The event was recorded and is available below. There were some technical issues in the event, but my presentation starts at 4h01m44s.</description></item><item><title>Basic Kodacolor identification aids</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/11/13/basic-kodacolor-identification-aids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/11/13/basic-kodacolor-identification-aids/</guid><description>Kodacolor lenticules Kodacolor sheen Your browser does not support the video format/codec.
Kodacolor film processed by deep-dolce Your browser does not support the video format/codec.</description></item><item><title>Practical cataloging principles</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/10/20/practical-cataloging-principles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/10/20/practical-cataloging-principles/</guid><description>I have typed out various specific cataloging procedures, I have pushed for certain cataloging changes, and I have specified requirements of our new cataloging system, but I have never spelled out the overarching principles I base my thoughts on.
This post is an attempt to start spelling out some possible overarching principles about cataloging. Perhaps some ideas make little sense outside of my organization due to organizational specifics, but I think at least some of these principles could be of use elsewhere.</description></item><item><title>Dangers of AI/ML hype</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/10/09/dangers-of-ai/ml-hype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/10/09/dangers-of-ai/ml-hype/</guid><description>There is a lot of &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; things happening in the AI/ML field, but as other, more poignant, people have stated, there is an abundance of downsides, pitfalls and straight up dangers lurking in the background of it all.
Ludicrous power and water usage (I wonder how many liters of water I wasted, in the creation of my little OCR script), the reproduction and ossification of the status quo through existing data biases reflecting current power structures etc; the list goes on.</description></item><item><title>video-ocr.py (and chatGPT)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/08/21/video-ocr.py-and-chatgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/08/21/video-ocr.py-and-chatgpt/</guid><description>Over the last year or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been dabbling with various scripts to manipulate video, metadata etc. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a wide range of experiments, amongst others grading film scans using Python and Jupyter notebooks (with massive help from Paul Duchesne) and trying use the IFIscripts for digital preservation of the scans of my grandparent&amp;rsquo;s Super8 home movies. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a light user of FFmpeg for years, but I think finally realised how low the bar for starting to use these tools in more advanced ways actually is.</description></item><item><title>Generic AV-cataloging</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/05/28/generic-av-cataloging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/05/28/generic-av-cataloging/</guid><description>Presentation held at the FIAF CDC Workshop &amp;ldquo;So Much More Than Non-Film: Cataloguing Film-Related Materials&amp;rdquo; in Stockholm 25.05.2023. Presentation focused on the ongoing migration work from the Mavis system to Axiell Collections at the National Library of Norway. Emphasis on how the LRM/EN15907 models can be applied in a generic manner for different types of materials. Some thoughts on &amp;ldquo;marrying&amp;rdquo; catalog models with traditional archiving models.
Link to PDF</description></item><item><title>Making reference images for grading tinted film</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/05/09/making-reference-images-for-grading-tinted-film/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/05/09/making-reference-images-for-grading-tinted-film/</guid><description>Digitising autonomous colours poses a range of challenges (&amp;ldquo;chromatic callier-effect&amp;rdquo;1, autonomous colours falling outside scanner spectral sensitivities2, etc.). There is no perfect solution or equipment to overcome these challenges though. Every institution has to come up with a solution based on educated guesses and the equipment available - Settle on something pragmatic and document what you do!
In my case, the available equipment is the DFT Scanity (and the MWA Nova Spinner).</description></item><item><title>Preservation metadata at the NLN</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/04/25/preservation-metadata-at-the-nln/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/04/25/preservation-metadata-at-the-nln/</guid><description>Presentation for FIAF CDC Preservation/Restoration Documentation Task Force about current and future(?) practices of documenting preservation processes at the moving image archive of the National Library of Norway. Examples based on film scanner/post-processing processes, but future aims are general and can be applied to other processes as well.
Link to PDF</description></item><item><title>Risoprint "Utsikten"</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2020/12/01/risoprint-utsikten/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2020/12/01/risoprint-utsikten/</guid><description>Three layer risoprint of a photography processed using Stochaster.</description></item><item><title>Pleasuredome backdrops</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/11/05/pleasuredome-backdrops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/11/05/pleasuredome-backdrops/</guid><description>Video backdrops for a club night at Lokal bar, Trondheim. Made using the LZX Vidiot, 3trinsRGB+1c, BPMC premium cable and an assortment of video mixers. Youtube excerpts</description></item><item><title>Getaway boat</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/07/20/getaway-boat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/07/20/getaway-boat/</guid><description>Music video/visuals for KEVINTHECREEP - Getaway boat. Made with a simple sound reactive LZX Vidiot patch and a BPMC Premium Cable. Youtube</description></item><item><title>Cherokee '93</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2016/06/06/cherokee-93/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2016/06/06/cherokee-93/</guid><description>Mix of southern 90s rap, with an emphasis on Memphis. Micro run of 20 tapes made at Tapedub, Berlin. Bandcamp</description></item></channel></rss>