<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dangers of AI/ML hype</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/10/09/dangers-of-ai/ml-hype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/10/09/dangers-of-ai/ml-hype/</guid><description>There is a lot of &amp;ldquo;cool&amp;rdquo; things happening in the AI/ML field, but as other, more poignant, people have stated, there is an abundance of downsides, pitfalls and straight up dangers lurking in the background of it all.
Ludicrous power and water usage (I wonder how many liters of water I wasted, in the creation of my little OCR script), the reproduction and ossification of the status quo through existing data biases reflecting current power structures etc; the list goes on.</description></item><item><title>AV basic pyramid of needs</title><link>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-11-30-archival-needs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-11-30-archival-needs/</guid><description>Frontfanger her.
Behovspyramide for arkiver. Hva trenges for bevaringsplanlegging? I hvilken rekkefølge
Inventory
Hva man har (gjenstand) hvor det er (plassering) Hva man har (tilstand) Hvor det kommer fra (proveniens) Hva man har (innhold) Rettigheter (avtaler gjenstand/innhold)
Bevaring (passiv) Bevaring (aktiv)
Tilgjengeliggjøring (metadata) Tilgjengeliggjøring (gjenstand/innhold?)</description></item><item><title>The digital domain is not magically different</title><link>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-10-30-digitalanalog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/draft/2023-10-30-digitalanalog/</guid><description>Background Master thesis about private home video collectors and torrent networks The point might have become slightly obscured by the details of my examples (brazillian ET etc.) Realisation and key tenet The digital and the analog is exactly the same the same but different wrapping/interfacing The digital has materiality The digital mirrors structures of the analog world The thought of digital domain as profoundly new/magical is damaging to discussion/debate You don&amp;rsquo;t have to do things in new ways, many times you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item></channel></rss>