<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Presentation on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/presentation/</link><description>Recent content in Presentation on Torbjørn Bakken Pedersen's home page</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Preservation at the National Library of Norway</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024/05/29/digital-preservation-at-the-national-library-of-norway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024/05/29/digital-preservation-at-the-national-library-of-norway/</guid><description>Presentation at the Digital libraries: storage for now and forever conferenence hosted by the IFLA Preservation and Conservation Center at the National Library of Poland. The presentation is a crash course through digital storage and digital preservation practices at the National Library of Norway over the past 20 years. It concludes with current status and our future plans.
Link to PDF
The event was recorded and is available below. There were some technical issues in the event, but my presentation starts at 4h01m44s.</description></item><item><title>Generic AV-cataloging</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/05/28/generic-av-cataloging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/05/28/generic-av-cataloging/</guid><description>Presentation held at the FIAF CDC Workshop &amp;ldquo;So Much More Than Non-Film: Cataloguing Film-Related Materials&amp;rdquo; in Stockholm 25.05.2023. Presentation focused on the ongoing migration work from the Mavis system to Axiell Collections at the National Library of Norway. Emphasis on how the LRM/EN15907 models can be applied in a generic manner for different types of materials. Some thoughts on &amp;ldquo;marrying&amp;rdquo; catalog models with traditional archiving models.
Link to PDF</description></item><item><title>Preservation metadata at the NLN</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/04/25/preservation-metadata-at-the-nln/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023/04/25/preservation-metadata-at-the-nln/</guid><description>Presentation for FIAF CDC Preservation/Restoration Documentation Task Force about current and future(?) practices of documenting preservation processes at the moving image archive of the National Library of Norway. Examples based on film scanner/post-processing processes, but future aims are general and can be applied to other processes as well.
Link to PDF</description></item></channel></rss>